Okay, I'm going to choose a really big font, and
現在我要 選擇一個大字體
then I'll try a really small font.
然後我將嘗試小字體
So I picked display three here, which is 56sp.
因此選擇3號字體 高度是56sp
And remember to, add an attribute before the tag is closed.
記住 應該在標記封閉之前 增加屬性
So I'll hit enter here and then add textSize attribute.
因此我按一下 進入這裏 增加textSize屬性
Cool.
很好
And then the text is giant over here.
然後 字體在這裏變大了
Now I can try a smaller size, of maybe some body text
現在我嘗試小字體 一種正文字體
which would be 14 SP, so I'll erase this and
高度是14 SP, 我將刪除這個
then say 14, and then it's tiny again, cool.
然後鍵入14, 字體變小了 很好
Okay, so we finished the first task.
我們已經完成第一個任務
The optional challenge was to try learning about the text appearance
另一個挑戰是 在Google Plus學習網站
attribute on your own from the Google Plus protip that I included a link to.
瞭解文字外觀屬性 我提供了連結
Let's open that up now.
讓我們打開它
So, this is an Android dev protip that was written by yours truly, for
這是Android開發學習網站
the Android developers Google Plus page.
由Androidg開發人員編寫 Google Plus 網頁
If you haven't already, you can follow the Google Plus page for
如果你還沒有見過這個網站 你可以查閱面向Android開發者的
Android developers, to get the latest news on Android development.
Google Plus網頁 瞭解最新的Android開發訊息
Or if you'd prefer Twitter, you can follow our account there.
或者 如果你更喜歡Twitter, 也可以查閱我們的帳號
So basically in this short pro tip, I talk about
在這個學習視訊中 我講解
again how too many font sizes can be visually distracting for your user.
怎樣使用不同的字號 從視覺上吸引使用者
So you can use the recommended font sizes in the Material Design spec, or
你可以使用素材設計規范中 建議的字號
you can also choose from a standard set of type sizes, provided by Android,
也可以從Android提供的 標準字號集中選擇合適的字號
which is small, medium and large.
有小號 中號和大號
So instead of text size, you said the Android TextAppearance attribute
這時不需要設定字號 而是把Android TextAppearance屬性
to be androidTextAppearanceLarge, or you can set small or medium.
設定為androidTextAppearanceLarge, 也可以設定為small或medium
These TextAppearance values map to these SP font sizes.
這些TextAppearance值 對於應這些SP字號
So with these ever changing Android
利用這些不斷變化的Android屬性
then your code will automatically get the new value.
你的代碼將會 自動獲得新值
Using text appearance is grea,t because you don't have to worry about specific
使用文字外觀屬性是一個很好的方法 因為你不需要設定
SP values, and
具體的SP值 而且
you can still be consistent with other apps on the device.
可以與其他設備上的 應用程式保持一致
For example, for a title you can use large, for
例如 標題可以 使用大字號
a list item you can use medium, or for a caption you can use small.
清單項目可以使用中字號 字幕可以使用小字號
So these are good buckets to work with.
這些都是很好用的工具
You can try the mat in our code by copying this line here.
在我們的代碼中 你可以嘗試這個方法 複制這裏的這行代碼
You can use cmd+Ccor you can use ctrl+c if you're on a Windows machine.
可以使用cmd+C 如果使用Windows電腦 可以使用ctrl+c
Go over to our code here.
轉到代碼的這個位置
I'm going to delete this text size line,
我要刪除這個字號代碼行
because we're going to add text appearance.
因我們要增加 文字外觀屬性
Hit command V or control V.
按command V或control V.
So now android text appearance is text appearance large.
現在android文字外觀 已經設定為大號字體
And you can see that the preview has updated to have the larger font size.
你可以看到 預覽已經更新 變為更大的字體
That's pretty neat, right?
看上去很不錯 是吧
And you can also change this to be medium or small.
還可以更改為 中號或小號字體
So in general, this is really useful to know,
總來的說 我們應該知道
if you don't want to declare specific SP values.
你不需要知道 具體的SP值
So if you have no idea which SP values you want to use,
如果你不知道使用什麼SP值
you can just pick from small, medium, large.
你可以選擇小號 中號或大號字體